cabinetoffice.gov.uk 2013-01-16

# Privacy policy | Cabinet Office

This page explains our privacy policy and how we will use and protect any information about you that you give us when you visit this website.

This privacy statement only covers Cabinet Office websites. It does not cover all sites that can be linked to from this site, so you should always be aware when you are moving to another site and read the privacy statement on that site.

### What information do we collect?

From time to time, you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name and email address) in order to receive or use services on our website. Such services include newsletters, email updates, have your say, website feedback, send to a friend.

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable the Cabinet Office and its service providers to provide you with the services you select. Any information you provide to the Cabinet Office will only be used by us, our agents and service providers and will not be disclosed unless we are obliged or permitted to by law to do so.

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on cabinetoffice.gov.uk or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on cabinetoffice.gov.uk, we may use whatever information is available to us, about you, to stop such behaviour.

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as you use the service you have requested, and remove it in the event that the purpose has been met or when you no longer wish to continue your subscription.

### Feedback

We welcome your feedback. If you contact us asking for information, we may need to contact other government departments to find that information. If your question is technical, we may need to pass it to our technology suppliers.

We do not pass on any of your personal information when dealing with your enquiry, unless you have given us permission to do so. Once we have replied to you, we keep a record of your message for audit purposes.

### Email subscriptions

Some areas of this website offer email updates. To receive these email updates, you need to register, giving: your email address; a user name; and password. We do not share the information you provide with any third parties and we protect it in accordance with the Data Protection Act.

### The Data Protection Act

Under the Data Protection Act, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it.

We do not pass on your details to any third party or other government department.

### Access to your information and contacting us

If you wish to see our records of any correspondence you have sent to us, or if you have a query or complaint about this privacy policy or about the site, you can contact us by using the feedback form.

### Cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don’t have to give the same information several times during one task
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there’s enough capacity to ensure they are fast
  * analysing anonymised data to help us understand how people interact with government services so we can make them better

You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through [How government websites use cookies](http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/SiteInformation/DG_197506).

Learn how to [remove cookies set on your device](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1).

#### Our use of cookies

There are two types of cookie you may encounter when using [www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk](http://www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/):

**First party cookies:** these are our own cookies, controlled by us and used to provide information about usage of our site.

**Third party cookies:** these are cookies found in other companies’ internet tools which we are using to enhance our site, for example Facebook or Twitter have their own cookies, which are controlled by them.

##### First party cookies

[www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk](http://www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/) uses cookies in several places – we’ve listed each of them below with more details about why we use them and how long they will last. This applies to the website [www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk](http://www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/). This does not apply to subdomains / subsites - please check individual sites for their own privacy policies and cookies listings.

We will endeavour to let you know before we store a cookie on your computer.

###### Cookies set by the Cabinet Office website

**Name** | **Purpose** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---|---  
AWSELB | Allows load balancer routing the same client to the same application server | Random data | 15mins  
has_js | Set by CMS for batch functionality | Random data | Session  
NO_CACHE | Sets a short-lived cookie on form submissions so that you could be certain that you would get refreshed pages after form submissions  |   |    
  
##### Third party cookies

We use a number of suppliers who may also set cookies on their websites on its behalf. The Cabinet Office website does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

**Provider** | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More info**  
---|---|---|---  
Flickr | 

BX

b

s

localization  

| Flickr image slideshow | [Flickr Privacy policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/flickr/details.htm)  
YouTube | 

use_hitbox

PREF

GEO

| YouTube video | [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)  
CarbonCulture | csrftoken | To guard against cross-site request forgery |    
Yottaa | yvts |   | [Yottaa Privacy Policy](http://www.yottaa.com/privacy "Yottaa Privacy Policy ")  
  
AddThis | 

loc

ssc

uid

uvc

psc

dt

di 

TweetWally | 

PHPSESSID

__utma

__utmb

__utmc

__utmz 

Google Analytics | 

__utma

__utmb

__utmc

__utmz

| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)  
  
#### How to control and delete cookies

We will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.

However, if you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our website, or indeed any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The ‘Help’ function within your browser should tell you how.

Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your machine as well as more general information about cookies.

Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our website.

If you wish to view your cookie code, just click on a cookie to open it. You'll see a short string of text and numbers. The numbers are your identification card, which can only be seen by the server that gave you the cookie.  
For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.

To opt-out of third-parties collecting any data regarding your interaction on our website, please refer to their websites for further information.

### Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
